Cameron Delay | Software Engineer

Mashpee, MA | (508) 423-8366 | camdelay16@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer transitioning from a successful career as an executive administrative assistant. My experience honed my skills in project management, communication, and problem-solving, as I consistently managed complex projects and communications for multiple executives, delivering exceptional results even under pressure. I am a highly collaborative team player and now seek to leverage these skills, along with my growing proficiency in software development, to build user-friendly and efficient applications that solve real-world problems.

SKILLS

Languages | JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python.

Libraries and Frameworks | Express.js, React.js, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Django, Flask.

Databases | MongoDB, PostgreSQL.

Other | Autho, RESTful Routing, JSON, Postman, Github, VSCode, Canva, FontAwesome, Netlify, Adobe, ADP, Agiloft, Box, Concur, Confluence, Diligent Boards, DocuSign, G-Suite, Jira, Microsoft Office Suite, Sage Intact, Slack, Smartsheet, Stampli, Survey Monkey, Trello, Visio, Zoom.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Accomplish | Live Site | Github

- Developed a responsive to-do list for users to track, categorize, and check off to-dos.
- Built a full stack application in 1 week with full CRUD operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Created an API using Django to enable reliable access, storage, and manipulation of user data.
- Technologies used: JavaScript, Bootstrap, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Canva, CSS3

Craftopia I Live Site I Github Front End I Github Back End

- Created an application for users to collaborate by posting directions to crafts, view other user's crafts, and leave reviews on each other's crafts. Users can also favorite crafts they like which will add the craft to their dashboard.
- Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) to build a full stack application with full CRUD operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Created an API using Express to enable reliable access, storage, and manipulation of user data.
- Technologies used: React, JavaScript, Canva, CSS3, MongoDB, Express, Node.js

BundleUp | Live Site | Github Front End | Github Back End | Github Group Project

- Collaborated with a team of 4 developers to create an initial application for users to post events and deals in their
 area and RSVP to events or get deals. I have since updated code across the front and back ends to create a
 cohesive project.
- Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) to build a full stack application in 1 week with full CRUD
 operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Created an API using Express to enable reliable access, storage, and manipulation of user data.
- Technologies used: React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS3, MongoDB, Express, Node.js

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Executive Assistant | The Health Initiative | Remote | May 2022 - Sept. 2024

Supported the Co-Founders and C-suite team with day-to-day operations. Highly effective and proactive administrative
professional with a proven ability to manage complex executive schedules and logistical operations for multiple Csuite executives, consistently exceeding expectations and delivering exceptional results even under significant time
constraints.

- Expert in advanced calendar management and meeting logistics, adept at anticipating needs, resolving conflicts, and securing high-priority meetings and travel arrangements, often with tight deadlines and challenging constraints.
 Successfully implemented streamlined processes to improve team efficiency.
- Demonstrated mastery of a wide range of software and tools, including Asana, to manage projects and communications effectively, consistently enhancing workflow efficiency and optimizing organizational systems.
- Adept at building and maintaining strong relationships with internal and external stakeholders, effectively leveraging
 these networks to achieve organizational objectives and secure strategic partnerships, leading to significant
 improvements in overall efficiency and productivity.
- A creative problem-solver with exceptional adaptability and resilience, consistently delivering exceptional results in the face of unexpected challenges and last-minute changes. Proven ability to identify and implement solutions to improve team processes and workflows.

Senior Administrative Assistant | SEIU 775 Benefits Group | Seattle, WA/Remote | Sept. 2016 - Aug. 2021

- Directly supported the Chief Legal Officer (CLO) and Chief Operations Officer (COO), who manage three Taft-Hartley
 Trusts and two Washington non-profit corporations, with various projects and heavy calendar scheduling for board
 meetings, committee meetings, and internal and external meetings.
- Promptly followed up with internal and external correspondence for scheduling inquiries, Trust Board support, expense reimbursements, invoice approvals, trustee onboarding administrative procedures, fiduciary insurance, and inquiries for the Legal and Trust Benefits Administration (TBA) departments.
- Drafted, edited, and proof-read Executive Director reports, Board actions, Minutes, PowerPoints and other documents in preparation for meetings.
- Created and oversaw Legal Department and Trust Board Operations budgets in excess of one million dollars on behalf of CLO and COO.
- Oversaw the vendor selection, buildout, data entry and implementation of a Contract Management Software for the Legal department to improve efficiency by creating an automated contracting process with intake request module, several permission settings, automated workflows, reports, executive dashboards and integration with DocuSign.
- Found various software to help improve efficiency and built intranet sites to support the Legal and TBA departments locate important documents, organizational updates, useful weblinks, project tasks, and view deadlines on their respective department team calendar.
- Partnered with the Director of the Project Management Office to facilitate change management within the organization by creating an organizational alignment process, business tools, and database to support cross functional alignment, effective communication, consistency, and efficiency across the organization's Shared Services and TBA departments.

Product Supervisor/Visual Merchandiser | Fossil Inc. | Las Vegas, NV | Nov. 2014 - July 2016

- Served as a team leader and operative resource for sales associates to improve efficiencies, while successfully
 overseeing the creative and strategic product-merchandising processes and improved overall organization of retail
 space.
- Analyzed and reported in-depth sales data regarding product penetration, used to make critical decisions with regard to capitalizing on incoming revenue and connecting with the corporate office to maintain consistent inventory levels.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Bootcamp Immersive | General Assembly | Remote

Sept. 2024 - Dec. 2024

Full-time immersive program in Software Engineering consisting of 480+ hours of project work, professional training, and mentorship. Executed end-to-end Fullstack Development and developed a portfolio of individual and group projects, and stakeholder presentation; worked fully remote with teams using Agile methodologies and iterative development.

Psychology B.A. | University of Massachusetts, Amherst **Communication B.A.** | University of Massachusetts, Amherst

Sept. 2009 – Sept. 2014 Sept. 2009 – Sept. 2014